Milton R. Konvitz Additional Papers /4085
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Milton R. Konvitz Additional Papers
1925-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Konvitz, Milton R.
/4085
58 cubic feet
58 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
7980465
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 20, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 27, 2016
Biographical / Historical
March 12, 1908 - September 5, 2003
Milton Konvitz, a Cornell University faculty member and authority on constitutional and labor law, and civil and human rights, died Sept. 5 at the age of 95. Konvitz was a founding faculty member in the School of Industrial and Labor Relations from 1946 until his retirement in 1973. He was also a professor in Cornell's Law School.
Konvitz is perhaps best known for his American Ideals course, which he taught to more than 8,000 students over the course of his career, never giving the same lecture twice. "I saw the U.S. Constitution as it has been interpreted as a magnificent depository of our ideals, both individual and social," he said. His course exposed students to the great intellectual thinkers and philosophers throughout history whose writings had shaped those ideals. They included Sophocles, whose play Antigone is Cornell's New Student Reading Project this year. One student he influenced was U.S. Supreme Court Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg, Cornell Class of 1954, who considers him a mentor.
At Cornell Konvitz also was a founder of the university's Department of Near Eastern Studies and Program of Jewish Studies. "I felt it was essential for a college interested in the humanities not to leave out Hebrew language and literature," he said. "And the knowledge of Jewish history, which began 4,000 years ago and has contributed to civilization no less than Greek, Roman or English history, is important to today's students -Jewish and non-Jewish." He often hosted students at his Ithaca home and helped start the first Kosher dining option at Cornell, Young Israel House.
In addition, for nearly 30 years he directed the Liberian Codification Project, which drew up the official body of statutory laws that is still in force in the Republic of Liberia today, despite the current political upheaval there. Konvitz also edited the opinions of Liberia's Supreme Court and received the Grand Band of the Order of the Star of Africa, the highest award given to foreigners, as well as an honorary degree from the University of Liberia, one of seven honorary degrees he received in his lifetime.
Active as a scholar and writer until his death, he wrote books and articles on American constitutional law that won him wide recognition and were cited in U.S. Supreme Court opinions. Among his nine books is Fundamental Liberties of a Free People: Religion, Speech, Press, Assembly, which was republished earlier this year with an expanded introduction by him that is strongly critical of the Rehnquist Supreme Court. Other books include A Century of Civil Rights (1983) and Judaism and Human Rights (2nd ed. 2001). He also edited a dozen volumes, including two on American philosopher Ralph Waldo Emerson, whose thinking shaped his views. One Emersonian idea he absorbed was that readers give life to books, which Konvitz recast as follows: "It is in their hearing that students bring life to the words, the thoughts, the teacher."
Konvitz was born in Safed, Palestine (now Israel ), in 1908, the son of a rabbi. He immigrated to the United States in 1915 and became a naturalized citizen in 1926. He received a bachelor's degree in 1929 and a law degree in 1930, both from New York University, and a Ph.D. in philosophy from Cornell in 1933. Before joining Cornell's faculty, he was one of three assistant general counsels to Thurgood Marshall at the NAACP Legal Defense Fund for three years.
He is survived by his wife, Mary, of Oakhurst, N.J.; a brother, Phillip, of Elberon, N.J.; a son and daughter-in-law, Josef and Isa, of Paris, France; and two grandsons, Eli and Ezra. Josef Konvitz, who grew up in Ithaca, is now an official at the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4039: Milton R. Konvitz Papers
Konvitz, Milton R. (Milton Ridvas), 1908-2003; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
7980465
- Miscellaneous Publications (Box 1)
  - A Study in Attitudes Towards Racial and Religious Minorities and Towards Women (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Teenage Pregnancy (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Equality: Language Barriers and Women (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitutional Aspects of the Right to Limit Childbearing (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - White House Conference Report (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Report on Government Operations - Senate Intelligence Activities - Books 1 and 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Government Operations Book 3 and June 1975 CIA Commission Report (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Conference Report - October 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dynamics of Growth - Federalism (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Civil Rights and Black America (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Comparative Studies in Federalism: Canada (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Future of Federalism in the 1980s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - German Speaking Jews and Zionism (1987) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Martyrdom and Resistance (1986-87) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Timely Does Not Mean Never: Notice to Congress of the Iran Arms Deal (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ACADEME American Association of University Professors (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Salzburg Seminar Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Civil Rights Update; The Nation Honors Martin Luther King, Jr. (1986) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - National Security Record; A Report on the Congress and National Security Affairs (1986) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Near East Report (1986) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Libya and the American Economic Boycott: A Possible Scenario for the Future (1986) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Campus Report for Accuracy in Academia (1985) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Israel Histadrut Foundation (1985) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Pension Plans: The Human Resource Management Perspective (1985) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Jewish Monthly "Censorship: Do Parents Know Best?" (1986) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Middle East Review - Asia and the Middle East (1985-86) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - News from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem (1985) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, Inc. (1986) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Review of Development in the Middle East (1986) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - News Bulletin, American Jewish League for Israel (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cults are Changing (1985) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Zionist Formation Service (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Employee Relations Law Journal (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Future (1987) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Tikkun - A Quarterly Jewish Critique of Politics, Culture and Society (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Israel Law Review (1986) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - The Future (1987) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - National Civic Review (1987) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Midstream - A Monthly Jewish Review (1986) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Encounter" (1986) (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Myths and Facts (1982) - A Concise Record of the Arab-Israel Conflict (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - New York University Magazine (1986) (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Columbia - The New Carnegie Hall (1986) (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - How the Minimum Wage Destroys Jobs (1987) (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - The History of Social Scientific Inquiry (1986) (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cornell Law Review Vol. 72, 2 - Jan. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association Series; Dec 28-30, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Political Communication and Persuasion - Vol. 3, Number 4, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Political Communication and Persuasion - Vol. 3, Number 4, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association Series - Dec. 28-30, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - The American Philosophical Association - Jan. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association Series - Dec. 28-30, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Bulletin: Des Leo Baeck Instituts - 75/1986 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association: April 28-30, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Cornell Law Review - Vol. 7, Number 6, Sept. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Funding/Taxation Brochures; Center for Advanced Studies of Behavioral Sciences (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Political Communication and Persuasion - Vol. 4 #1 and 2 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "Law and Society Review" (1987) and "Israel Law Review" (1986) (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Subject Files (Application for Fellowships-Discard) (Box 2)
  - Members Associate in the World Conference of Jewish Organizations (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lists of Universities Teaching Hebrew 1974 (US not included) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Association for Jewish Education (1973) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture (1971) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fellowships in Jewish Education Leadership (1973) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brandeis University Newsletter (1973) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Judaic Studies in Institutions of Higher Learning (1974) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Committee on College Youth and Faculty Programs (1973) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hebrew Culture in American Secular Institutions f Higher Learnings (1947-1960) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fran Meder to Harvard - Jewish Studies Expand to our 200 Campuses (1973) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture - Purpose and Program (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Trend Toward Jewish Studies on Campus (1973) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "To Leave Your Mark" and "Religion in the University a Terminal Case?" (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conservative Judaism (1973) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Studies in American Liberal-Arts Colleges and Universities (1966) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Analysis, Jewish Academies: New Signs of Life in a "Disaster Area" (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Rule and Place of Jewish Studies in American Colleges and Universities (1971) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The New Jews on Campus: Myths and Reality (1969) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Jews in American Universities Since the End of the 19h Century (1970) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Free Jewish University - An Experiment in Jewish Study (1973) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Association for Jewish Studies Newsletter (1974) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Seven Settings for Jewish Learning (1973-74) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Undergraduate Courses in the Study of the History of Judaism and of Hebrew Language and Texts (1973-74) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hebrew College Bulletin (1974) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Doctoral Dissertations and Masters' Theses Accepted by American Institutions of Higher Learning (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture: Guidelines (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Study of Training Programs Supported by the Memorial Foundation (1965-73) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Report of the Commission on Formal Jewish Studies in Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - American Association for Jewish Education (1972-73) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Commission on Jewish Studies in College and Universities (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Analysis: The Long Range Significance of the New Jewish Consciousness on Campus (1972) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Academic Jewish Studies: Objectivity or Advocacy? (1973) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Association for Jewish Studies Newsletter (1973) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Background Material for Annual Meeting Board of Trustees of Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture (1973) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture (1965-73) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Jewish Studies in American Colleges and Universities (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Jews in American Universities Since the End of the 19th Century (1943-70) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture (1970/71) (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Fifth Annual AJS Conference (1973) (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Subject, Correspondence & Miscellaneous; Lecture (Box 3)
  - The Economist - A Journal for Promoting Unity (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Judaism and the Spoliation of Nature (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Justice in the Grate (1960) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Biblical Studies in Memory of H.C. Alleman (1960) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Essays in Honor of Soloman Freeshof (1964) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Relation of the Individual to Political Society in Ancient Israel (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Biblical Foundations of the Democratic Tradition by Robert Gordis (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Essays in Honor of Solomon Freeshop (1964) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Freedom of Speech, Thought and Religion (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Just Society in Israel (1969) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Human Relations in Jewish Law (1967) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Self-Incrimentation and the Halalchah (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kingship and the Gods: A Study of Ancient Near Eastern Religion as the Integration of Society of Nature (1948) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Natural Law and the Old Testament (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Just Society in Israel (1969) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Rabbinic Judaism and the Problem of Egoism (1938) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Biblical Foundations of the Democratic Traditions (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Right of Dissent and Intellectual Liberty in the Jewish Tradition (1940-50) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - News Clippings: Jewish Organizations and Perspectives (1966-69) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Naturalism and Historical Understanding (1967) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Natural Law in the Jewish Tradition (1969) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rights of Privacy Act of 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Poverty and the Great Society - The Jewish Approach (1966-67) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Freedom of Speech, Thought, and Religion" (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Freedom Religion, etc. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - HUC Cincinnati Church and State Issues (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Judaic Studies (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - France Magazine 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Trends in Housing (1987) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 15th Annual Roundup: The Pedagogic Reporter (1987) (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Near East Report (1987) (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Employee Relations Law Journal (1986-87) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - The Future (1986) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Restrictions on Criminals' Rights to Profit from Accounts of Their Crimes (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Report on Regulation of Charitable Solicitations (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Civil Liberties Misc. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Religion Misc. and ACADEME (Nov.-Dec. 1986) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - International Migration 3 and 4 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Law and Society Review - Vol. 20, No. 4 1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Social Science Research Council (1985-86) (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Article Clippings 1 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Zionism (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Liberian Studies (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Religion (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Religion Part 2 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - ILR Misc. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Valentine (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Office File Letters (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Publications (Box 4)
  - Human Rights (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pending (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ghetto 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Lilienthal: Important to Keep (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Zionism (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Cornell Documents (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Supreme Courts (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Misc. News clippings (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Publications (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Social Security Rates of Return for Today's Young Workers (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Courses of Study 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cornell University Courses of Study 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cornell University 1986-87 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Visa (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Evolution (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Secular Humanism (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Directory of Cornell Social Scientists and Economists 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Reports to Deans (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 1985 ILR Alumni Directory (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Publications and Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Bicentennial of the United States Constitution Calendar - 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Legacy of Horace M. Kallen (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Norman Levine's Editions (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Salzburg Newsletters (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - AGLU (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Litigation Docket 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Law School: Cornell General Announcements (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University Faculty Handbook (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Heritage Foundation: "Background" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hebrew Publications (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - CLAL (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Judaism (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Blackwells 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Humanism and Civil Liberties (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - John Deweg: The Later Years (1925-53) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Cornell News and Info (1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Cornell News and Info (2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Cornell News and Info (3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Cornell International Law Journal (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Law and Society Review (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Students Papers & Publications (Box 6)
  - Articles Editor Letter (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - National Jewish Resource Center and CLAL (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Judaism (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - American Jewish Congress v. Carter (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Southern Education Report (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Petition for Writ of Certiorari: In Re Burrus (copy) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Can a State Close all of its Public Schools in Order to Avoid Desegregation (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Provision of Legal Services to Defendants, with Special Attention to Tompkins County (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Employment Testing Procedures and Seniority Systems and Title VII (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Historical Development of the Strike and Picketing (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Look" - April 3, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cornell International Law Journal (Winter 1987) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Yiddish Language (1969/70) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Des Leo Baeck Instituts (1968) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - International Logic Review (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The LA Follete Committee: Labor and Civil Liberties in the New Deal (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Labor Problems (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Electing Union Officers (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Milton R. Konvitz (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Teachers, School Boards, and Collective Bargaining (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Columbia Law Review (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Syracuse Scholar (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Presidential Studies Quarterly Fall 1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Presidential Studies Quarterly Fall 1984 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Reports of the President and the Treasurer 1985 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Censorship (Winter 1966) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Censorship (Fall 1965) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Censorship (Spring 1966) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Censorship (Summer 1965) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Censorship (Spring 1965) (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Censorship (Fall 1964) (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Censorship (Winter 1967) (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - The future: 1892 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Middle East Review (Fall 1986) (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Cornell Law Review (July 1986) (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Censorship (Fall 1966) (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Censorship (Summer 1966) (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Review of Achievements (1985) (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Subject, Correspondence & Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Judaism (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Articles and Letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Middle East (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Law Reviews (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Medical Records (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Helsinki Reports (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Helsinki Process and East West Relations (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Konvitz (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - New Perspectives (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Articles and Letters (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Cooperation in Europe and Espionage (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Economics, Budget, and Power Program (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - The Pedagogic Reporter - November 1987 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "Civil Rights and Political Justice" (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Individual Abilities and Comparable Worth (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - International Migration (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Reagan's Secret Wars" (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "Friend of the Court" (1947-82) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The American Philosophical Association (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Social Science Research Council (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Publications (Box 8)
  - The Intercollegiate Review (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Midstream" Vol. 8-10 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Measure" No. 61-64 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Law and Society Review" (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - New Articles Part 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - New Articles Part 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - New Articles Part 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Affairs (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Judaism Part 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Judaism Part 2 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Jewish Social Studies" and "Israel Law Review" (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Civil Rights Pt. 1 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Civil Rights Part 2 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Cornell (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Columbia (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Social Justice (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Academe (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Studies (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Baker Meeting (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Bill of Rights (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Cornell Committee (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - University Meetings (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Telephone Info (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Interview (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "Employee Relations Law Journal" (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - "The Journal of Law and Religion" (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Philosophia: Philosophical Quarterly of Israel (Dec. 1984) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Oxford University Press: General Catalogue 1986-87 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - "The Institute for Advanced Study" - Annual Report 1984/5 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - The World & I - January 1986 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Reprints (Box 9)
  - "The Cornell Daily Sun" (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Go and Study" - Essays and Studies in Honor of Alfred Jospe Part 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Go and Study" Part 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Go and Study" Part 3 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Go and Study" Part 4 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Conscience, Natural Law, and Civil Disobedience " from "Law and Man" (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Conscience, Natural Law, and Civil Disobedience in the Jewish Tradition" by Milton Konvitz Part 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Conscience, Natural Law, and Civil Disobedience in the Jewish Tradition" by Konvitz Part 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Conscience, Natural Law and Civil Disobedience in the Jewish Tradition" by Konvitz Part 4 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Konvitz Essays (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "A Journal Devoted to Halacha Jewish Thought and Education" (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Individual Conscience and Group Consciousness: Religious Liberty in Israel and the US" - Konvitz Part 1 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Individual Conscience and Group Consciousness: Religious Liberty in Israel and the US" - Konvitz Part 2 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Individual Conscience and Group Consciousness: Religious Liberty in Israel and the US" - Konvitz Part 3 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Manuscript Materials (Box 10)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 4 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 5 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 6 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 7 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 8 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Various Milton Konvitz Essays Part 9 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Religion (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Civil Rights and Politics (Box 10, Folder 11)